Guide to the University Art Gallery Records, 1938-2005 UA.90.8.16.1
ULS Archives & Special Collections
University Art Gallery Records
1938-2005
ULS Archives & Special Collections
University of Pittsburgh. University Art Gallery
UA.90.8.16.1
13.75 Linear Feet (11 boxes)
The University Art Gallery manages the University of Pittsburgh's art collection and regularly hosts exhibitions of artwork. This collection contains information and catalogs for many of the exhibits hosted by the University Art Gallery from 1938 to 2005.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Scope and Content Notes
This collection contains information and catalogs for many of the exhibits hosted by the University Art Gallery from 1938 to 2005.
Acquisition Information
Deposited by the University Art Gallery in 2012 and 2015.
History
The University Art Gallery (UAG) can trace its origins to the relocation of the University of Pittsburgh's Fine Arts Department to the seventh floor of Cathedral of Learning in 1937. When the department moved into the Cathedral of Learning there was also space for the Fine Arts Library and a small gallery for temporary exhibitions. Upon completion of the Henry Clay Frick Fine Arts Building in 1965, the UAG relocated to that space.
The UAG maintains the University of Pittsburgh art collection, which totals over 3,000 objects. Drawing from the University's holdings, as well as those of other museums and traveling exhibits, UAG hosts several exhibitions each year. Other shows feature work completed by University faculty and students.
University of Pittsburgh; Exhibition catalogs; University of Pittsburgh. University Art Gallery
- Exhibitions of the University Art Gallery, 1938-2005; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series contains files on many of the exhibits held by the University Art Gallery from 1938 to 2005. These files contain records pertaining to the planning of the exhibtis, including correspondence, loan information, provenance research, and more. Also included are the exhibit catalogs, which provide information about the pieces of art that were part of each exhibit.
  - Exhibitions of Paintings by Pittsburgh Artists of the Nineteenth Century, November 1938 - June 1939 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Exhibition of French Paintings of the Nineteenth Century, April 22 - May 17, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Pictures of People Looking at Pictures Exhibition, February 15 - March 15, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Contemporary Mexican Prints, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Russel Smith (1812-1896) Romantic Realist: Paintings, Watercolors, Drawings, November 10 - December 10, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Exhibition of Paintings to Commemorate the Centenary of Henry Clay Frick, December 19, 1949 - February 15, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - History of Enamels: VII-XX Century, March 13-April 8, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - An Exhibition of the History of Art from Private Collections, April 20-May 16, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Calligraphy: The Symbolic LIne in the Art of Writing and in the Arts of Form Exhibition, April 15-May 11, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Fulbright Designers, c. 1959 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Exhibition of Water Colors, Pen and Ink Drawings by Jeannette C. Shirk, February 8-March 3,1960 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - A Wonderland of Steel: Exhibition of Needlepoint Tapestries by Mildred T. Johnstone, November 10-December 9, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - None Can See the Limits of Its Reach: An Exhibition of Eighty-Six Books Selected from the Henry Ckay Frick Fine Arts Library and Held in Memory of John Gabbert Bowman (1879-1963), Chancellor of the University of Pittsburgh (1921-1945), Spring 1964 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - The 1967 United Jewish Federation Exhibition: 28 Twentieth Century Painters and Sculptors - Art Acquisition Records (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - The 1967 United Jewish Federation Exhibition: 28 Twentieth Century Painters and Sculptors - Clippings, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - The 1967 United Jewish Federation Exhibition: 28 Twentieth Century Painters and Sculptors - Correspondence, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - The 1967 United Jewish Federation Exhibition: 28 Twentieth Century Painters and Sculptors - Event Programs and Catalogues, September 25-October 4, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - The 1967 United Jewish Federation Exhibition: 28 Twentieth Century Painters and Sculptors - General Event Information, September 25-October 4, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 17th Century and Early 18th Century Italian Prints, October 8-November 13, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - A Collector's Choice: Selected Examples from the Jay Leff Collection of Art, September-December 1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Contemporary Spanish Paintings and Drawings Exhibition, December 1967 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - One-Cent Life Show, February 18-March 30, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Georges Roualt Prints Exhibition, April 3-28, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - French Posters of the 1890s on loan by the French Embassy to the United States, April 29-May 11, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - L'Art Nouveau Prints from the London Arts Group of Detroit, Michigan Exhibition, May 1-31, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Vasarely "X" Exhibit, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Studio Arts Faculty Exhibition, October 15-November 8, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - The 1968 United Jewish Federation Exhibition, November 24-December 26, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Aspects of the Architecture of the Univesrity of Pittsburgh: 1787-1969, January 21-February 14, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Contemporary Latin American Prints, January 15-February 15, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - An Exhibition of Basic Design Works by Students of William S. Huff, February 25-March 25, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Photographs Before Surrealism, March 16- April 5, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Photography of Harry Callahan, March 15-April 4, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - The Chateau of Chambord, April 8-20, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - American Painting: The 1950s Exhibition, July 6-August 3, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - The Gosman Collection, September 4-October 10, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 36-38)
  - The Legend of John Henry by Palmer C. Hayden (1890-1973), November 1969 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - An Exhibition of Medieval Brass Rubbings by Kathleen Cairns, December 7, 1969-January 4, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Oleta Maria Zouka, January 5-17, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Selected Paintings and Sketches by Reginald Marsh - Clippings and Publications, January 17-February 22, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Selected Paintings and Sketches by Reginald Marsh - Promotional Material, January 17-February 22, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Selected Paintings and Sketches by Reginald Marsh - Correspondence and Financial Records, January 17-February 22, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - An Exhibition of Chinese Art from the Collections of the Honorable Hugh Scott, Dr. Yi T'ung Wang, and Dr. Bliss Wiant - Exhibition Catalogues, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - An Exhibition of Chinese Art from the Collections of the Honorable Hugh Scott, Dr. Yi T'ung Wang, and Dr. Bliss Wiant - Promotional Materials, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - An Exhibition of Chinese Art from the Collections of the Honorable Hugh Scott, Dr. Yi T'ung Wang, and Dr. Bliss Wiant - Guest Lists, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - An Exhibition of Chinese Art from the Collections of the Honorable Hugh Scott, Dr. Yi T'ung Wang, and Dr. Bliss Wiant - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - An Exhibition of 20th Century Prints from the Albirght-Knox Gallery, May 12-June 7, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - John Rhoden Exhibitions - Press Releases and Clippings, September-October 1970 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - John Rhoden Exhibitions - Correspondence, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - John Rhoden Exhibitions - Photographs and Catalogues, September-October 1970 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - John Rhoden Exhibitions - Financial Records, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - La Belle Epoque - Correspondence, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - La Belle Epoque - Financial Records, October-November 1970 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - La Belle Epoque - Clippings and Magazines, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - La Belle Epoque - Promotional Materials, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Spirit of the Comics - Catalogues and Clippings, November 1970 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Spirit of the Comics - Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Spirit of the Comics - Financial Records, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Early Wills and Legal Artifact Display, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Allegheny County Bar Association Centennial, November 1970-January 1971 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Studio Arts Faculty Exhibition, December 1970-January 1971 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Joseph M. Katz Collection - Catalogues, February 14-March 14, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Joseph M. Katz Collection - Inventory and General Information, February 14-March 14, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Joseph M. Katz Collection - Promotional and General Material, February 14-March 14, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Joseph M. Katz Collection - Clippings and Photographs, February 14-March 14, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Joseph M. Katz Collection - Financial Records, February 14-March 14, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Joseph M. Katz Collection - Correspondence, February 14-March 14, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - The Architecture of Peter Berndtson, March 28-April 18, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - "Christopher Wren: Architect" Exhibit, April 22-May 16, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 2nd Annual Student Exhibition, May 28-June 25, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Latin American Studies Exhibition, June 23-30, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Cybernetic Sculpture Environment by Wen-Ying Tsai - Correspondence, September 19-October 17, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Cybernetic Sculpture Environment by Wen-Ying Tsai - Financial Records, September 19-October 17, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Cybernetic Sculpture Environment by Wen-Ying Tsai - Promotional Materials and Catalogues, September 19-October 17, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Alcoa Collection of Contemporary Art - Correspondence at Financial Reports, November 5-December 4, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Alcoa Collection of Contemporary Art - Catalogues, November 5-December 4, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Malbin Collection: The 20th Century Print - Correspondence, December 14, 1971-January 16, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Malbin Collection: The 20th Century Print - Financial Records, December 14, 1971-January 16, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Malbin Collection: The 20th Century Print - Gallery Inventories, December 14, 1971-January 16, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Malbin Collection: The 20th Century Print - Promotional Materials, December 14, 1971-January 16, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Tiepolo Exhibition, February 11-March 15, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - An Exhibition of Korean Painting, March 1972 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Studio Arts Faculty Exhibition, March-April 1972 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Portraits and Figure Studies by Harold Neal, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Interpretation: Design with Plant Material, May 3-4, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - America Collects III: Pennsylvania Quilts, September 12-October 8, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Art and Landscape of Italy: Too Late to be Saved?, October-November 1972 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Opus Donatelli, November-December 1972 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Studio Arts Graduate Student Exhibition, December 1972-January 1973 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Diaghilev and Russian Stage Designers, March 6-29, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - A Selection of Prints by Flemish and Dutch Artists of the 16th and 17th Centuries, February 20-March 29, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - 100 Photographs from the George Eastman House Collection - Correspondence, April 5-21, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - 100 Photographs from the George Eastman House Collection - Financial Records, April 5-21, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - 100 Photographs from the George Eastman House Collection - Inventory and Promotional Materials, April 5-21, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Imperial Carpets from Peking - Catalogues and Event Planning, February 15-March 18, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Imperial Carpets from Peking - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Imperial Carpets from Peking - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Imperial Carpets from Peking - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Imperial Carpets from Peking - Correspondence, 1974-1976 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Imperial Carpets from Peking - Financial Records, February 15-March 18, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - The Price of Genius: Drawings by Carl Frederick Hill (1849-1917) and Ernst Josephson (1841-1906) - Catalogues, September 20-October 26, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - The Price of Genius: Drawings by Carl Frederick Hill (1849-1917) and Ernst Josephson (1841-1906) - Correspondence, September 20-October 26, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - The Price of Genius: Drawings by Carl Frederick Hill (1849-1917) and Ernst Josephson (1841-1906) - Financial Records, September 20-October 26, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - The Price of Genius: Drawings by Carl Frederick Hill (1849-1917) and Ernst Josephson (1841-1906) - Promotional Materials and Photographs, September 20-October 26, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Antiquity Reborn: An Exhibition of Prints, Drawings, and Books from the Collection of the Frick Fine Arts Library, Museum of Art of the Carnegie Institute, and University Art Gallery, November 8-December 8, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Needlework: Portrait of an Unknown Artist, November 8-December 8, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - The Sistine Chapel for the First Time, January 31-March 2, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Calder's Circus, December 20, 1974-January 19, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Death, Love and the Maiden - Catalogues, March 14-April 20, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Death, Love and the Maiden - Correspondence, March 14-April 10, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Death, Love and the Maiden - Financial Records, March 14-April 20, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Death, Love and the Maiden - Promotional and Planning Materials, March 14-April 20, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Forgeries and Their Detection - Correspondence, September 26-November 2, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Forgeries and Their Detection - Financial Records, September 26-November 2, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Forgeries and Their Detection - Promotional and Planning Materials, September 26-November 2, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 15-16)
  - Henry Moore Prints 1969-1974, November 15-December 21, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Soup Tureens from the Campbell Museum, January 23-February 29, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Master Drawings: Purpose and Technique, January 29-February 29, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Color of the Middle Ages: A Survey of Book Illumination Based on Color Fascimiles of Medieval Manuscripts, March 12-April 18, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Confluences: The Architecture of Urban Design Associates - Correspondence, October 26-December 5, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Confluences: The Architecture of Urban Design Associates - Planning and Promotional Materials, October 26-December 5, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 22-23)
  - America Underfoot: A History of Floor Coverings from Colonial Times to the Present, February 1-27, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Oriental Rugs, Marson Exhibition and Sale, March 1977 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Art in Nineteenth Century Pittsburgh, March 10-April 3, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Selections from the Collection of Walter Read Hovey, March 11-April 3, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Paintings by David Summers, March 11-April 3, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - A Special Destiny: Women in America 1750-1815, March 16-April 24, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Black American Art from the Barnett-Aden Collection, September 17-October 23, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - A Holiday Celebration: Rumanian Folk Customs as Interpreted by Stefan Stirbu, December 2-18, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Art Nouveau: Works by Tiffany, Mucha, Toulouse-Latrec, Galle, Beardsley, and Others, January 13-February 12, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Jacob Kainen (1909-2001): American Printmaker, February 24-March 19, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Contemporary Yugoslavian Prints, April 7-23, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - David Summers: New Paintings 1977-1978, August 29-September 24, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Close Observation: Oil Sketches by Frederic Edwin Church (1826-1900), November 16-December 20, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Photography by Clyde Hare (1927-2009), January 27-February 18, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Works of Art from the University's Collections and Recent Acquisitions, May 17-June 17, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Contemporary Printmaking: A Selection from the Collection of Ashland Oil, Ltd., November 5-25, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Photography by Duane Michals, October 23-December 14, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - The Frank J. Mangano Collection, December 2, 1979-January 20, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Fine Books and Printing: A Sampling of Books from the Henry Clay Frick Fine Arts Library, December 14, 1979-January 31, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Ivan Leonidov (1902-1959): Russian Visionary Architect, February 1-22, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Contemporary Latin American Paintings and Prints, February 5-24, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Three Essays in Exhibition, March 18-April 13, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Studies of Light: Paintinsg by David Summers, May 10-June 5, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Contemporary Andean Art, September 4-21, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Life: The First Decade - Great Photographs from Life Magazine, January 5-February 22, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Medieval Art and Medieval Revivals, March 12-April 26, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Broad Spectrum: Works by the Faculty of the Philadelphia College of Art and Eugene Feldman (1921-1975), Pennsylvania Artist, May 8-June 26, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Photographs by Brodsky and Marisco, September 27-October 18, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Contemporary American Realists: Works on Paper, October 24-December 6, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - British Prints, November 6-December 6, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Palladio, Architectural Models and Related Materials, January 30-March 14, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Barbizon Paintings from the Speck Collection, January 30-March 14, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Rem Bahautdin: Ukrainian Metalwork, April 1-4, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Kenneth Snelson, Sculpture, April 17-May 23, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Recent Works by Boanerges Mideros, Ecuadorian Artist, April 2-4, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Cityscapes: Photographs by Duane Michals - Historic Photographs of Pittsburgh and a Photographic Competition, August 31-September 15, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Czechoslovak Artists Abroad, October 29-31, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Yugoslav Drawings, Current Trends, November 5-21, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Studio Arts Faculty and Student Show, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Reflections and Realities: Selections from the Collection of Kitty and Harold Ruttenberg, January 30-February 27, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Sculpture in Pittsburgh Public Places, April 9-May 27, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - 1983 Hazlett Award Exhibition, July 17-August 21, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Etchings by Gary Edson, September 7-October 9, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Urban Pulses: The Artists and the City, New Works and Installations by Nine Pittsburgh-based Artists, October 9-November 6, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - The Lowenthal Gift, November 12-December 11,1983 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Italian Portrait Drawings 1400-1800 from North American Collection, January 20-February 26, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Works on Paper by Patricia Tobacco Forrester and Harriet Shorr, March 2-April 1, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Pittsburgh's New Skyscrapers: An Exhibition Sponsored by the Architectural Studies Program, March 8-April 1, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Second Harmarville International: A Juried Exhibition of Works by Handicapped Artists, April 7-April 17, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Homage to John Kane (1860-1934), May 12-17, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Croatian Exhibition, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - 1984 Hazlett Memorial Awards Exhibition for Visual Arts: Paintings by Henry Koerner and Jewelry by Stanley Lechtzin, August 26-September 23, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Door Gods and Other Chinese Household Deities, November 3-25, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Houses by Pittsburgh Architects, November 3-25, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Icons and Paintings by the Romanian Artist, Oltea Maria Zuca, January 20-February 28, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Bernard Farmer's (1919-2002) Cats, from the Lowenthal Gift, January 20-February 28, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Contemporary Paintings and Sculpture from the Dominican Republic, March 1-24, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Hagia Sophia Through Byzantine Eyes, March 15-April 30, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Samuel Yellin (1885-1940), Metalworker, and Samuel Yellin's Wrought Iron Masterpieces in Pittsburgh, March 29-April 30, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Perceiving Antiquity: Four Small Exhibitions: Piranesi's Rome, Illustrating the Classics for Children, The Real Thing, Popular Antiquity, May 3-15, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Primal Whispers, A Collaborative Installation by Dorothy Forman, Adrienne Heinrich and Jo Ann Pratt, June 2-30, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - 1985 Hazlett Memorial Awards Exhibition for the Visual Arts: Charles Fahlen, sculpture, Anthony Buba, film; Lary Fink, photography; and Mitchell Guirgola, architecture, July 7 - August 15, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bicentennial of Pitt/UAE file exhibitions (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - The One Hundred Friends of Pittsburgh Art Collection at the Pittsburgh Public Schools, 1916 – 1959, an Exhibition Celebrating the 75th Anniversary of the Associated Artists of Pittsburgh, September 7-29, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Paul Binai, New Paintings, Japonisme, 1984 – 1985, November 17 - December 15, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Two Rediscoveries: Anthony Angarola and William G. Mayer, February 1- 23, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Neil Sapienza: Portfolio China and Russian Artists of the 1980s: Paintings and Prints, April 12-27, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Generations Together, Intergenerational Art Exhibition, May 9- June 1, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Exhibition of Kazuaki Kita Art, August 3 -10, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - 1986 Hazlett Award Winners for Excellence in the Arts in Pennsylvania, August 17 - September 21, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Master Weavers of India, October 11 - November 23, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Paintings from the Gimbel Collection at the University of Pittsburgh, January 9 - Frebruary 15, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - The Cathedral of Learning: Concept, Design, Construction, March 19 - May 17, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 14-15)
  - Drawing the Figure, September 15 – November 8, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - The Post Industrial Steelscape: Photographs by Margaret Evans and Watercolors by Suzanne Roth, November 17 – December 20, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Life: The Second Decade, January 15 – March 1, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Reid and Stuhldreher, a Centennial Exhibition, March 19 – April 17, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - The University Collects, April 22 – May 22, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Pittsburgh Society of Sculptors Annual Juried Exhibition, June 2 -3, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Dutch Geometric Abstraction in the 80s, August 28 – October 2, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 1-3)
  - Two Exhibitions in honor of the 70th Anniversary of the "Pittsburgh Declaration" October 28, 1918: Photographs of Joseph Sudek and Paintings and Prints by Albin Brunovsky, October 9 – November 6, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
  - The Codex Calixtinus and Related Manuscripts, October 27 – November 6, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Civic Visions: 20th Century City Planning in Pittsburgh, November 15 – December 18, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 20 Years of Czechoslovak Art: A Tribute to Jacques Baruch, December 1988 – January 1989 (Box 6, Folder 8)